Steven Goldberg

O'Fallon, MO

Phone: 856-630-8763 | Email: stevengoldbergm@gmail.com
LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/stevengoldbergm/ | GitHub: github.com/stevengoldbergm/
Portfolio: https://stevengoldbergm.github.io/react-portfolio/

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in psychology and imaging operations for mortgage banking institutions. Dedicated employee - internally promoted three times during his previous 8 year tenure. Eager to learn new things and share knowledge with others. Strives for expertise and always looks to understand the "why" behind the "how."

Technical Skills

Technical Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Handlebars.js, MySQL 2, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Bootstrap, Bulma, SASS **Applications:** Git Bash, Visual Studio Code, MySQL Workbench, MongoDBCompass, Insomnia, MS Office Suite

Projects

MovieMate 3.0

GitHub: https://github.com/stevengoldbergm/movie-mate-3.0

Deployed Site: https://movie-mate-3.herokuapp.com/

- **Summary:** MERN stack application utilizing oMDB API to pull movie data and YouTube API to pull movie trailers. Users can add friends, plan watch parties, and write movie reviews.
- **Responsibilities:** Project planning, Front-end development, Code refactoring, Heroku launch, Heroku MongoDB Integration, Troubleshooting, and Testing
- Languages and Tools: MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Axios, Bulma, GraphQL, Apollo, SASS, JSON WebToken, BCrypt, Heroku

Tech Bloa!

GitHub: https://github.com/stevengoldbergm/tech-blog

Deployed Site: https://tech-blog-stevengoldbergm.herokuapp.com/

- **Summary:** Message board application built using the Model View Controller design pattern. Users can post articles and comment on existing article posts.
- Responsibilities: Full application design and development
- Languages and Tools: MySQL 2, Sequelize, DotEnv, Express, Express-Handlebars, Express-Session, BCrypt, Bootstrap

Experience

Citi O'Fallon, MO
Ops Support Specialist 5 2019 – 2022

Worked with project management as a liaison and subject matter expert for the Mortgage Imaging team. Implemented technology changes. Monitored numerous risk control tasks to ensure the business was in compliance. Generated hourly ad hoc volumetric data reports. **Key Accomplishments:**

Developed training for remote workers to perform digital tasks during the pandemic

- Lead effort to refactor department procedures during a change in business software
- Developed and documented procedures for new tech and trained staff accordingly

Ops Support Assistant 4

2017 - 2019

Continued to lead a team in Retail Mortgage Imaging Operations, now with additional responsibilities. Managed workflow and monitored production to ensure service level agreements were met daily. Worked interdepartmentally to update processes and procedures. **Key Accomplishments:**

- Utilized online resources to learn Visual Basic for Applications (VBA)
- Performed integration testing on a new Mainframe shell (IBM PCOMM)
- Created multiple end-user technology solutions to improve productivity/accuracy

Ops Support Assistant 1

2016 - 2017

Lead a team of 12-24 people in Retail Mortgage Imaging Operations. Managed workflow and monitored production to ensure service level agreements were met daily. Worked interdepartmentally to update processes and procedures.

Key Accomplishments:

- Built business relationships between multiple departments
- Worked with new business contacts to develop new training materials.
- Documented procedures and created structured training guides for processors
- Became Citi Lean certified

Document Support Specialist 1

2014 - 2016

Performed an expansive list of (over 120) daily imaging production tasks across four separate branches of business: Retail Mortgage, Mortgage Default, Banking, Retail Cards. Developed mastery of Citi's mainframe data systems. Developed mastery of Microsoft Office Suite **Key Accomplishments:**

- Consistently exceeded expectations in performance reviews
- Performed a special project as a temporary member of the Quality team
- Built training materials and reorganized resources for new-hires on Quality team

Education

Full Stack Web Development Certificate: Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS

Bachelor of Arts in Psychology: University of Missouri: St. Louis, St. Louis, MO Accomplishments: Psychology Department Chair's List, Spring Semester 2013